They took his daughter. He'll take their lives.
Taken is a action, thriller film directed by Pierre Morel.
Bryan Mills, a former government operative, is trying to
reconnect with his teenage daughter Kim.
After reluctantly agreeing with his ex-wife to let Kim go to Paris on
vacation with a friend, his worst nightmare comes true.
While on the phone with his daughter shortly after she arrives in Paris, she
and her friend are abducted by a gang of human traffickers.
Working against the clock, Bryan relies on his extensive training and skills to track down the
ruthless gang that abducted her and launch a one-man war to rescue his daughter.
Bryan Mills, played by Liam Neeson.
Kim Mills, played by Maggie Grace.
Lenore St. John, played by Famke Janssen.
Jean-Claude Pitrel, played by Olivier Rabourdin.
Sam Gilroy, played by Leland Orser.
Mark Casey, played by Jon Gries.
Taken is a 2008 English-language French action-thriller film directed by
Pierre Morel and written by Luc Besson and Robert Mark Kamen.
It stars Liam Neeson, Maggie Grace, Leland Orser, Jon Gries, David
Warshofsky, Katie Cassidy, Holly Valance and Famke Janssen.
In the film, Bryan Mills, an ex-CIA officer, sets out to track down his teenage daughter Kim and her best
friend Amanda after they are kidnapped by Albanian human traffickers  while on vacation in France.
Taken was released in France on February 27, 2008.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, and was a financial
success, grossing $226 million against a $25 million budget.
Numerous media outlets cited the film as a turning point in
Neeson's career that redefined him as an action star.
It also launched a franchise, consisting of two sequels and a television series.
The film explores themes of rescue, paris, france,
kidnapping, prostitution, sex trafficking.
The tone is intense.